Finding Aid for the Synanon Foundation Records LSC.0342
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Films
  - Tomales Construction: Camera Original, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_719_006; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:06:56) 250 feet (Box 719, Case 6)
    Can labeled: "Earth moving at Walker - Laying cable at Ranch / Tomales Construction - Orig." Sign: "Thickened Sound Department of Music" Tomales Bay was one Synanon site, at the Marconi Estate.
  - Synanon on Film - December: Work Print, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_719_007; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:08:20) 300 feet; Pattern of stress on perfs and one tear missing one perf in last quarter of film. Eastman stock printed alongside Kodak stocks, unclear which is print stock and which may have been printed in from original. (Box 719, Case 7)
    Synanon archive #134b. Side of can labeled: "A 25 + 35 - Dec. Synanon on Film - W.P. - Composite Track - Pic. - 1972" Dental care, baby care, Charles Dederich depicted.
  - Or Die: Composite Print, circa 1967; yrlsc_342_719_008; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:18:45) 675 feet; Slight cupping and brittleness. One tear and perf damage previously repaired with tape. (Box 719, Case 8)
    Synanon archive #289. Synanon Films label on can: "Title: Or Die / No. 24-1 / Property of: Synanon Foundation, Inc. / Running time: 18:00 / Black and White" Also labeled: "Archives Film Circulation Library" Features talk with "The Tunnel Back: Synanon" on table, possibly author Lewis Yablonsky?
  - Synanon Commercial #1: Camera Original, circa 1973; yrlsc_342_719_009; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:02:46) 100 feet (Box 719, Case 9)
    Printed-in on tail: "'B' Roll - Synanon Commercial - Title 44-31" Head leader: "48-2 Synanon Foundation Commercial #1" Locations in San Francisco - Oakland
  - Aerial Footage of Ranch & Bay: Camera Original, circa 1971; yrlsc_342_719_010; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:03:28) 125 feet; Also printed on edge: EKco P 9/71 (Box 719, Case 10)
    Can labeled: "Audio/Visual #70 - Aerial Footage of Range + Bay" Very dark, underexposed footage.
  - "Blood Donation Footage": Camera Original, circa 1967; yrlsc_342_719_011; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:04:10) 150 feet (Box 719, Case 11)
    Can labeled: "Audio/Visual #66 - Blood" Blood donation? Drawing blood.
  - Ranch Footage: Camera Original, circa 1970; yrlsc_342_719_012; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:04:10) 150 feet; Also printed on edge: EKco P 9/71 (Box 719, Case 12)
    Can labeled: "Audio/Visual #73 - Aerial Footage of Bay + Ranch" Underexposed, dark.
  - Aerial Footage of Oakland and San Francisco: Camera Original, circa 1970; yrlsc_342_719_013; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:03:28) 125 feet; One significant emulsion scratch throughout reel. Edge information also includes: "EKco P 9/71" (Box 719, Case 13)
    Can labeled: "F11 Oak: S.F." and "Audio/visual #72 - Aerial Footage of Oakland + SF" Aerial urban views. Appears to include Synanon's location at Athens Athletic Club in Oakland. Unsure of SF locations.
  - Oakland School: Camera Original, undated; yrlsc_342_719_014; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:03:28) 125 feet; Regular indents on non-perf side from being projected in a silent, double-sprocket projector. (Box 719, Case 14)
    Can labeled: "Audio/visual #62 - Oakland School" and "Trix Roll #2" Children at a school. Home movie.
  - Synanon on Film - December: Fullcoat Mag, 1972; yrlsc_342_719_015; 1 sound recordings (1 16mm full-coat mag; Duration: 00:08:20) 300 feet; Vinegar syndrome. Editing notes written on emulsion side near splices. One appears to connect portion of sound to "hatchery" (Box 719, Case 15)
    Synanon archive #134a. Side of can labeled: "A 25 + 35 - Dec. Synanon on Film - W.P. - Composite Track - Pic. - 1972"
  - Instant Guide to Synanon: Composite Print, 1973; yrlsc_342_720_001; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:09:01) 325 feet; Color fading. (Box 720, Case 1)
    Handwriting printed-in: "Instant Guide to Synanon: Synanon Foundation" Promotional film for Synanon styled as a Q&A.
  - Instant Guide to Synanon: Composite Print, 1973; yrlsc_342_720_002; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:09:01) 325 feet; Color fading. Oldest generation, but much more scratched. Bizarre two feet of label adhered toward head; came off during scanning & spread fine white dust but the rest of the adhesive residue won't come off. (Box 720, Case 2)
    Printed-in handwriting at tail: "Instant Guide to Synanon: Synanon Foundation". Stamped at head: "Permafilm Protected / Hollywood" Promotional film for Synanon styled as a Q&A.
  - Instant Guide to Synanon: Composite Print, 1973; yrlsc_342_720_003; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:09:01) 325 feet; Color fading. Very light scratches throughout. (Box 720, Case 3)
    Handwriting printed-in: "Instant Guide to Synanon: Synanon Foundation." Stamped at head: "Hollywood Permafilm Protected" Promotional film for Synanon styled as a Q&A.
  - Instant Guide to Synanon: Composite Print, 1973; yrlsc_342_720_004; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:09:01) 325 feet; Color fading. It appears that the negative this print was made from had an emulsion scratch down one side. One instance of perf tear previously fixed with edge tape. Base scratches worse at head. (Box 720, Case 4)
    Red "Do Not Rewind Film" leader at tail. Handwriting printed-in: "Instant Guide to Synanon: Synanon Foundation." Promotional film for Synanon styled as a Q&A.
  - Instant Guide to Synanon: Composite Print, 1973; yrlsc_342_720_005; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:09:01) 325 feet; Color fading. One perf torn out and previously repaired with edge tape. (Box 720, Case 5)
    Red "Do Not Rewind Film" tail leader. Handwriting printed-in at tail: "Instant Guide to Synanon: Synanon Foundation." Green "Synanon Department of Films" tail leader. Promotional film for Synanon styled as a Q&A.
  - Instant Guide to Synanon: Composite Print, 1973; yrlsc_342_720_006; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:09:01) 325 feet; Color fading. Run of stretched or torn perfs near tail, along with many splices (cement or tape). May be footage missing. Two small portions of metallic tape in between two perfs and covering part of the respective frames at ~75 and ~200' into reel. Significant emulsion scratch ~150' into reel. (Box 720, Case 6)
    Red "Do Not Rewind Film" tail leader. Handwriting printed-in at tail: "Instant Guide to Synanon: Synanon Foundation." Green "Synanon Department of Films" head leader. Promotional film for Synanon styled as a Q&A.
  - Basic Training: Composite Print, circa 1975; yrlsc_342_720_007; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:07:38) 275 feet; Color fading. (Box 720, Case 7)
    Printed-in handwriting at head: "Synanon w/o 0185-004." Printed-in handwriting at tail: "TAILS TION SYNANON 'BASIC TRAINING #2'"
  - Basic Training: Composite Print, circa 1975; yrlsc_342_720_008; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:08:20) 300 feet; One minor perf tear at head. Besides that and color fade, print is immaculate. Uncut. (Box 720, Case 8)
    Printed-in handwriting at tail: "W.O. 0185-004 'Basic Training' Synanon Foundation A-Wind Color Interneg." and "TAILS TION SYNANON 'BASIC TRAINING #2'"
  - Behind the Scenes at Synanon: Composite Print, circa 1965; yrlsc_342_720_009; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:06:56) 250 feet; Some perf tears (one particularly bad) at tail and a few during the countdown at head. (Box 720, Case 9)
    Behind the scenes of 1965 movie Synanon. Features Synanon House, actors from the movie, and Chuck Dederich.
  - Instant Guide to Synanon: Composite Print, 1973; yrlsc_342_720_010; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:09:43) 350 feet; Scratching worse at head. Edge repair tape previously used to fix perf damage at head. (Box 720, Case 10)
    "Hollywood Permafilm Protected" stamped at head. Written at head: "Synanon Foundation: Instant Guide to Synanon - Bulls <> Eye" Included with film: Portion of Daily Variety from May 18, 1976. Connection to Synanon or this film is unclear.
  - The Ids: Outtakes, undated; yrlsc_342_720_011; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:02:46) 100 feet; Segments of film spliced together and oriented inconsistently. All perforations line up, but subsequently some footage is upside-down and backwards. Order on reel does not match that of the digital transfer. Exact order of footage remains unknown. Splice tape is yellowing and there is some other tape residue at some splices. Some redox blemishes throughout. Torn perfs previously repaired with edge tape, but repair is sloppy. Tape on edges trimmed during inspection, but some perforations may be misaligned with tape. (Box 720, Case 11)
  - The Mechanical Dolls: Outtakes, circa 1968-1971; yrlsc_342_720_012; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:03:28) 125 feet; Some tape splices have residue from previous tape used, and/or redox blemishes from the previous tape. (Box 720, Case 12)
    Can labeled: "Outtaked - Black + White - Not viewed" Outtakes and title cards for "Mechanical Dolls," described by the cards as an "An enigmatic farce."
  - The Mechanical Dolls: Outtakes, circa 1968-1971; yrlsc_342_720_013; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:03:28) 125 feet (Box 720, Case 13)
    Can labeled: "Outtakes - Black + White - Not viewed" Footage appears to be from film "Mechanical Dolls."
  - Synanon Basic Training: Fullcoat Mag, undated; yrlsc_342_720_014; 1 sound recordings (1 16mm full-coat mag; Duration: 00:06:56) 250 feet; Vinegar syndrome (Box 720, Case 14)
    Written at head: "Synanon Basic Training #1 (...[illegible] Pilot)" Note with film: "Film Drawer" - "Synanon - Basic Training - 75-24-1 - 35-16"
  - Synanon Law Lecture #2: Dan Garrett: Fullcoat Mag (Reel 2 of 2), 1973; yrlsc_342_720_015; 1 sound recordings (1 16mm full-coat mag; Duration: 00:08:20) 300 feet; Vinegar syndrome. Very warped. Difficult to achieve smooth wind during inspection. (Box 720, Case 15)
    Synanon archive #179. Inside TODD-A0 16mm High Output Magnetic Film box labeled: "A40-2 - Synanon Law Lec. #2 [...] - Orig. - Master - Mag. Track - 16MM - Reel #2 - 1973" Side of box labeled: "A-40-2 [...] Lecture - 16 Mag. Track - Reel II of II - 1973" Written at head: "[...] Lecture 26ft advance Reel 2"
  - The Synanon Wedding Festival: Titles, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_720_016; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:02:46) 100 feet; White text on black background, though on color stock. (Box 720, Case 16)
    Processed by Kodak leader labeled: "Wedding Titles: to be cut into 'c' roll" Titles at beginning read: "Betty Dederich..." / "First day of Synanon..." / "Mother figure..." / "Producer." - These do not appear to be from Wedding Festival film. Remainder of titles (including film title card) match those in Wedding Festival film.
  - Bay to Breakers: Camera Original, circa 1973; yrlsc_342_721_001; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:19:26) 700 feet; Combination of seven original rolls of 100' each, with original slug in between identifying roll #. Unprocessed shape found at end of each roll, perhaps left behind by previously attached label. (Box 721, Case 1)
    Synanon archive #181a. Consolidated Film Industries box: "A-41 - Bay to Breakers - Orig - Pic. - 16MM - B+W - 1973" Removed portion of head leader labeled "Head" and with sticker "CFI ORIGINAL - DO NOT PROJECT" due to sticky adhesive of sticker. Remaining head leader labeled: "Head - 607BW40 - 5014230 - Rolls 2-8 - Synanon Foundation". Tail leader: "Foot - 607BW40 - Synanon Foundation - Bay to Breakers - Rolls 2-8 - 5014230 - 607BW40 Foot" followed by ~1' of black film. San Francisco Bay to Breakers runners in Synanon shirts, barbecue
  - Profile Charlie: Work Print, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_721_002; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:25:41) 925 feet; Light emulsion and even lighter base scratches throughout. Eastman 48 appears to be print stock, while the original edge information appears to be Kodak TXR or PXR. Date code unidentifiable. (Box 721, Case 2)
    Synanon archive #188a. Consolidated Film Industries box labeled: "A21 - Profile Charlie - WP-" and "Synanon Found. 286363 5x100 7277"
  - Upward Mobility: Workprint Outtakes, circa 1971-1972; yrlsc_342_721_003; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:13:53) 500 feet; Brittle tape splices left adhesive residue throughout the reel. Redox blemishes left on film where adhesive interacted with silver particles. (Box 721, Case 3)
    Original box labeled: "A-10 Upward Mobility - W.P. - Pic - 16mm - B&W - 1972 / 124" Exercising on beach, haircuts, stage performance.
  - 49ers at Synanon: Work Print, circa 1971; yrlsc_342_722_001; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:01:23) 50 feet (Box 722, Case 1)
    Synanon archive #187c. Box: "F 13 Trip Orig. & Workprint 187" Core label: "187c"
  - Badger in the Sierras - Track 1: Fullcoat Mag, 1972; yrlsc_342_722_002; 1 sound recordings (1 16mm full-coat mag; Duration: 00:08:20) 300 feet; Other editing notes on base throughout reel. (Box 722, Case 2)
    Synanon archive #122b. Box: "A-38 - Badger in the Sierras Orig. Mag track 16 MM #1 + 2 1972" / Tape on box: "A-38- Badger/Sierra's - 3 Magnetic Sound Tracks - 1972 edited" / Box label: "122" / Core label: "122b" Boxed together with 2 other full coat mag tracks.
  - Badger in the Sierras - Track 2: Fullcoat Mag, 1972; yrlsc_342_722_003; 1 sound recordings (1 16mm full-coat mag; Duration: 00:08:20) 300 feet; Some editing marks throughout. (Box 722, Case 3)
  - Badger in the Sierras - Track 3: Fullcoat Mag, 1972; yrlsc_342_722_004; 1 sound recordings (1 16mm full-coat mag; Duration: 00:08:03) 290 feet; Some editing marks throughout. (Box 722, Case 4)
    Synanon archive #122c. Box: "A-38 - Badger in the Sierras Orig. Mag track 16 MM #1 + 2 1972" / Tape on box: "A-38- Badger/Sierra's - 3 Magnetic Sound Tracks - 1972 edited" / Box label: "122" / Core label: "122c" Boxed together with 2 other full coat mag tracks
  - Steve Simon Lecture #5: Camera Original, 1973; yrlsc_342_722_005; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:04:51) 175 feet (Box 722, Case 5)
    Synanon archive #120. Found with two small rolls of 16mm (#120c) that were discarded for being clear and/or black. Rolls numbered with dot punches: "711405" and "727711405". CFI box: "A-40-5 [...] Lec #5 - Orig - Pic - 1972", "Synanon Foundation - 277178 - [...] #5 - 628BW08 - 1 Orig - 1 Print", and "A-40-5 - Synanon Game Lec. #5 - [...] - Orig. - Pic. - 16mm - B+W - 1973"
  - Profile Charlie: Camera Original, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_722_006; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:03:36) 130 feet; Emulsion slightly sticking to itself during unwinding. Frame count stamped on edges on emulsion side. Uncut film. (Box 722, Case 6)
    Synanon archive #118b. Paper bag: "Title: A-21, Property of: Synanon, Contents: OMG., Edge # BD0000-BD0111, L#16649, Charlie - Orig. Game" CFI box: "A-21 - [...] - Orig. - Pic. 1972"
  - Bay to Breakers: Camera Original, 1973; yrlsc_342_722_007; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:02:46) 100 feet; Emulsion slightly sticking together when unwinding. Minor liquid stains on emulsion side (possibly from incomplete drying during processing). Edge numbers printed on. Uncut film. (Box 722, Case 7)
    Synanon archive #181b. Consolidated Film Industries box: "A-41 - Bay to Breakers - Orig - Pic. - 16MM - B+W - 1973" People running the Bay to Breakers race in San Francisco. Wearing Synanon shirts. Images of runners stretching, so possibly at beginning of race.
  - Bay to Breakers: Camera Original Outtakes, 1973; yrlsc_342_722_008; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:04:10) 150 feet; 23 individual segments of film found wrapped around each other and spliced together with small sections of leader in between, with attempt to retain order in which film was wrapped. First 18 sections are silent. Final 5 sections were wound together in middle of larger reel with label "MISS. SHOTS." Three of these sections have sound, while the final two sections are silent again (GAF stock). Some sections had tape residue that was cleaned off with alcohol. In some cases redox blemishes have appeared on emulsion side where tape was. (Box 722, Case 8)
    Synanon archive #181c. Consolidated Film Industries box: "A-41 - Bay to Breakers - Orig - Pic. - 16MM - B+W - 1973" No original leader, but outside of film was taped together with labels: "181c" and "Bay to Breakers - Outs." Mostly appears to be outtakes of Bay to Breakers running. Sound portions appear unrelated and are transfers of video to film. Sound portions may be related to MAGIC FLUTE.
  - Profile Charlie: Work Print, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_722_009; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:03:36) 130 feet (Box 722, Case 9)
    Synanon archive #188b. Consolidated Film Industries box labeled: "A21 - Profile Charlie - WP-" and "Synanon Found. 286363 5x100 7277" Probable dupe of yrlsc_342_722_006. Printed-in handwriting of this film matches leader of that one.
  - Legal Suit: Camera Original, circa 1970-1972; yrlsc_342_722_010; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:05:33) 200 feet; Majority of film is in one orientation. Segment at tail changes orientation. This explains why original leader describes both ends as "head." (Box 722, Case 10)
    Synanon archive #194. Head leader: "HDS - Synanon - A-39 - 15083" Tail leader: "Synanon A-39 - 15083 - Tail" and "ORIG. - A-39 - Legal Suit Head." Footage perhaps related to 1972 libel suit against San Francisco Examiner. Film shows reporters at press conference, close-up shot of book "Pattern Interrogatories: Basic Facts" by Douglas Danner, and women xeroxing papers and organizing them.
  - Copyright: Work Print and Camera Original, 1972; yrlsc_342_722_011; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:01:56) 70 feet (Box 722, Case 11)
    Synanon archive #192. In Palmer Film Services paper bag: "Property of Synanon, Contents: Original, 20156." In plastic can: "Titles - Copyright 1972 - Original & Color W.P. - Pic. - 1973" yrlsc_342_722_011 contains two reels (a and b) that were found in can together. They have been combined onto one reel with leader & labeling in between. Emulsion is on same side throughout reel, but image flips between films due to differences in wind orientation. Title element: "© Copyright 1972. Synanon Foundation, Inc. All rights reserved." - only content
  - Basketball Game: Camera Original and Work Print, 1972; yrlsc_342_722_012; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:06:56) 250 feet; Work print found as many small segments that had previously been taped together (not spliced). Removed tape and spliced segments together with short leader slug in between. Some were reoriented to match direction of entire reel. Some tape residue remains. Many instances of redox blemishes throughout as a result of the original tape. (Box 722, Case 12)
    Synanon archive #132. Inside Palmer Film Services paper bag labeled: "Title: Roll 2 A-19 / Property of Synanon / Contents: 1-7361 - 1 lite wp - Edje # AJ0000-AJ0150 - C# 13853". Inside plastic can labeled: "A-19 Basket Ball Game - Orig. & W.P. - Pic. - 1972" Synanon basketball game playing a visiting team. Cheerleaders and band perform at halftime.
  - Synanon 4-H Club: Camera Original Outtakes, 1972; yrlsc_342_722_013; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:08:20) 300 feet; Many segments of film previously loosely taped together. Minor tear along soundtrack edge approx. 50 feet into reel. (Box 722, Case 13)
    Synanon archive #142a. Inside paper Palmer Film Services bag labeled: "Title: Syn 4-H A-27 / Property of Synanon / Content: Original - Edje # AD0000-AD0307 - L# 17483" Inside plastic can labeled: "A-27 - 4-H Club - Orig. - Pic. - 1972" Sign for "West Marine Jr. Livestock Show, Point Reyes, June 17-18" Children with animals.
  - Synanon 4-H Club: Camera Original Outtakes, 1972; yrlsc_342_722_014; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:06:20) 225 feet; Many segments of film previously loosely taped together. (Box 722, Case 14)
    Synanon archive #142b. Inside paper Palmer Film Services bag labeled: "Title: A-27 Syn 4-H / Property of Synanon / Contents: Original - L 18135" Inside plastic can labeled: "A-27 - 4-H Club - Orig. - Pic. - 1972" Children eating at restaurant / dining hall. 4-H club awards, charter for club. Children with animals, mostly horse and goat. Sign for Synanon 4-H Club.
  - The Synanon People Ranch: Copyright & Title: A & B Roll, 1973; yrlsc_342_722_015; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:02:46) 100 feet; A roll: Kodachrome stock only used for black leader. B roll: Double perf for title (black and white on color Kodachrome IIA) and single perf for black leader (Kodachrome II). Visible scuffs and some scratching on base side. (Box 722, Case 15)
    Synanon archive #193. Inside metal can labeled: "D-40 - People Ranch - Copyright & Title A&B Roll - Pic - 1973." A roll inside paper bag labeled: "People Ranch Copyright & Title / Property of Synanon / Contents: A roll. 20588" B roll inside paper bag labeled: "Copyright & Title 1st Scene People Ranch / Property of Synanon / Contents: B roll. 20588"
  - Bill Stern on "Lew Irwin Reports": Composite Reversal Print, 1960; yrlsc_342_722_016; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:08:20) 300 feet; Perfect condition. Kinescope. (Box 722, Case 16)
    Can labeled on side: "H 3 Bill Stern on Lew Irwin Reports" Labeled on lid: "Orig. # H3 Print / Audio Visual # 31 / Bill Stern [crossed out] Reports on Lew Irwin [end crossed out] on 'Lew Irwin Reports' " Lid also labeled with Palmer Film Services label: "#5 / Title: Bill Stern on 'Lew Irwin Reports' / Property of Synanon Foundation Inc. / [...] / Running time: 6:00 / Black and white / Sound"
  - Synanon's 10th Anniversary: Print, 1968; yrlsc_342_723_001; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:05:33) 200 feet; Frequent cement splices throughout. Appear strong, but may be weakened with tension. Significant base scratch in middle of reel; moderate emulsion and base scratches throughout. Printed-in edge info: Kodak N 82 (square)(circle) [1965] Safety Film (Box 723, Case 1)
    Synanon archive #109. Paper tape label that fell off can into box: "A-41 Synanon 10th Anniversary - Orig. - Printing Master - 1968" Boy holding sign near head: "Welcome to Synanon's 10th Anniversary Celebration Oct. 10-13" Other signs, celebration on Santa Monica beach outside Casa Del Mar and Armory buildings. Chain of Synanon people celebrating and holding hands.
  - NBC - Synanon's 10th Anniversary: Composite Reversal Print, 1968; yrlsc_342_723_002; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:08:20) 300 feet; Significant perf damage during countdown at head. Emulsion scratches are heavier at head and lighten throughout film. Base scratches remain relatively constant. (Box 723, Case 2)
    Synanon archive #110. Inside can labeled on side: "28/1 NBC Footage from 10th Year Celebration" Palmer Film Services label on lid: "aired NBC-TV Oct. 9, 1968, Tom Brokaw / Title: Footage from 10th Year Anniversary Celebration - 1968 / Property of: Synanon Foundation, Inc. [...] / Running time: 7:36 / Color / Sound" Note inside can identifies contents: "#28 NBC-TV, 10-9-68 FOOTAGE FROM SYNANON'S TENTH YEAR ANNIVERSARY CELEBRATION / Tom Brokaw - Santa Monica / Santa Monica Club [Casa Del Mar] - A Synanon Game ([...]), the kitchen, the service [gas] station, the School, an art workshop, the Hoopla / Interviews with [...], [...], and C.E.D. [Chuck Dederich]" Earlier generation copy of same content as yrlsc_342_723_003. Title taken from that copy.